让我来
Allow me.
我猜这不是你第一次
I gather this isn't the first time
帮女人穿衣服了
you've helped a woman into her clothing?
这也不是男人第一次帮你穿衣服了
Nor is it the first you've been helped into yours.
如果我跟你说是呢
What if I told you that it was?
我会说你的床伴真差劲
Why, I'd say you've kept poor company.
床伴会毁了姑娘的名声
Company has a way of damaging a girl's reputation.
一个过度关心自己名誉的姑娘
That was not the passion of a woman overly
可没有那种激情
concerned with her reputation.
那是好奇胜过了经验
That was the triumph of curiosity over experience.
有好几次胜利呢
Several triumphs.
至少三次
At least three.
两次
Two.
也许吧
Maybe.
到目前为止是两次
Well, two so far.
我热爱我的工作  坎贝尔先生
I love my work, Mr. Campbell.
我不想认为  我会任凭我的好奇心
I would hate to think that I'd allow my curiosity
危害工作
to jeopardize that.
我喜欢女人  埃里森小姐
And I love women, Miss Ellison.
你放心
You may rest assured,
我很谨慎
I am discreet.
出什么事了吗
Is something wrong?
快走
Move it. Come on.
没必要这样的
Ain't got to be this way.
你们可以让开
You boys could just step aside.
让我们过去
Let us pass.
怎么样
How 'bout that?
走
Go on.
地狱之轮  第四季第十集
喂
Hey!
不行
Uh-uh.
那可不是玩具
That ain't no plaything.
等我教你再用  好吗
You wait until I teach ya. All right?
貌似你也差不多够大了
Guess you're 'bout old enough.
走吧
Go on.
艾斯拉
Ezra!
我怎么跟你说的
What did I tell you?
不要一副装无辜的表情
Don't throw me a sassy look.
好多洗完了的衣服要挂起来
There's plenty of wash to be hung.
小溪里也有很多鱼
Plenty of fish in the creek, too.
去吧
Go on.
那个人
That man.
西德尼·斯诺  你抓到他了吗
Sidney Snow. Did you get him?
还没有
Not yet, no.
会抓住的对吗
You will?
那些人拒绝回去工作
The men are refusing to go back to work.
他们不肯踏出教堂
They won't set foot outside the church,
这我不能怪他们
and I can't say I blame them.
那些通缉令就在坎贝尔的桌子上
Those wanted posters are sitting on Campbell's desk.
我的肯定在最上面
I'm sure me own is right there on top.
西德尼·斯诺逃了
Sidney Ssnow turned tail
剩下的警官也不敢为难我们
and we just stood down the last of the deputies.
没人执行通缉令了
Ain't nobody to enforce them posters.
除了坎贝尔
Except Campbell.
我们把他杀了吧
I say we kill him.
已经死了不少人了
People got killed already.
工人们需要保证
The men need assurances.
我也是
As do I.
那我们就去把通缉令弄来
Let's go get 'em, then.
你留在这里
You stay here.
你们不得与我的圣徒饮酒
You'd have no drinking with my crew of saints,
亨廷顿先生
Mr. Huntington.
不得赌博  不得狂欢
No gambling or carousing.
那些是联太公司的问题  杨先生
No. Those are Union Pacific problems, Mr. Young.
只有爱尔兰工人才会那样
Found amongst an Irish labor force.
我的华工不会
I have none of that with my Chinese.
亨廷顿先生  我生来时一无所有
Mr. Huntington, I came into this world with nothing.
没有土地没有金钱没有接受过教育
No land, no money, no education,
没有任何前途
no prospects.
我年轻的时候经常食不果腹
As a young man, I often went without food,
于是我学会了品尝野麻雀的美味之处
and learned to savor the taste of wild sparrow.
多亏上帝恩赐  我在盐湖城的边缘
Through the grace of God, I have built a small empire
建立了一个小小的帝国
here on the edge of the great Salt Lake,
并在此铺设通往天国的路
where I am paving the way to Zion.
我取得如此成就  不是靠跟那些
I have not accomplished these things by doing business
把我来之不易的的成果看做理所应当之人
with men who would take for granted the hard-won bounty
或是那些想浪费我宝贵时间之人合作
of my table or endeavor to waste my precious time.
我钦佩您顽强的意志  先生
I admire your tenacious will, sir,
我也不想妄图浪费您的时间
and I wouldn't dream of wasting your time.
华工几乎各个方面都满足我的要求
Now, the celestials suit my needs in almost every way.
他们吃苦耐劳  身强体壮
They are hardy, healthy,
而且他们的工资非常低
and they work for pennies on the dollars.
但是他们喜欢动不动就停工
But they are prone to work stoppages,
这是我遇到的最头疼的问题
the worst of the which I am in midst of now.
他们吃什么
What do they eat?
-您说什么  -刚德森
- Excuse me? - Gundersen?
他们吃的食物
Their food.
你给他们什么吃
What do you feed them?
请原谅我的教区记录员
You'll have to excuse my ward clerk.
他是新来的
He's new to lion house.
所以还不懂我们的规矩
Doesn't yet understand our manners.
请原谅
Forgive me.
我只是个可怜的罪人
I am but a poor sinner.
一文不值  又无知
Unworthy. Ignorant.
只是一个笨蛋  请
A fool. Please.
我正要说
As I was about to say,
惰性是上帝的子女的一种普遍都有的特性
(HAM是指信耶稣，却非摩门的，他并不知道中国人是信什么，只是以为都是信这些的）
sloth is a sin common to sons of Ham
但在摩门教徒中，却不存在着这样的现象
but rare indeed among Mormons.
我随随便便就能给你召八百来个工人
I could easily provide you with over 800 workers.
*我憎恶北方佬的一切*
*I hates the yankee nation and everything they do*
*我也憎恶独立宣言*
*I hates the declaration of independence, too*
*我憎恶用我们的血汗造就的联邦*
*I hates the glorious union that's driven with our blood*
先生们
Gentlemen...
我们怎么会闹成这样
How did we get here?
我们闹成这样  约翰  是因为你恶意地
We got here, John, by way of your pernicious attacks
攻击了我的铁路和我的手下
on my railroad and my person.
铁路已经被腐败和无能给侵蚀了
Railroad is mired in corruption and incompetence.
-无能  -先生们
- Incompetence? - Gentlemen.
为什么闹成这样不重要
Don't matter how we got here.
我们必须找到新的共存方法
Got to find out way somewheres new.
州长  我的人要回去工作
Now, Governor, my men are goin' back to work.
我希望你能保证没人会去招惹他们
I want your guarantee they'll be left alone.
用这个请求来开始这场谈判
That request is an excellent starting place
真是再合适不过了
for this negotiation.
这不是请求
It is not a request.
你现在人数和武器都占劣势
You are outmanned and outgunned,
现在你必须撕掉那些债券告示
so now you will tear up those ridiculous bond notices
和通缉令  然后停止骚扰工人
and wanted posters and you will stop harassing the men.
不管你有多少枪我都是临时州长
I remain provisional governor no matter your number of guns.
你就算自称是这个世界的
You can call yourself provisional king
临时皇帝我都不在乎
of the world for all I care.
因此  我做不到无视法律的存在
As such, I will not abandon the enforcement of law.
我错在执法不够严厉
My mistake was tryin' to keep the matter parochial.
我现在知道  我的错
My mistake, as I see it now,
就是没有早点颁布戒严法
was not establishing martial law earlier.
要是有戒严法  我还不如留在密西西比
And I could have stayed in Mississippi for martial law.
谁都不喜欢戒严法
No one likes martial law,
不过本地缺乏可靠的执法官
but lacking any credible local law enforcement...
好吧
All right.
我干
I'll do it.
不过我不戴法警徽章
But I ain't gonna wear marshal's badge
而且我不是为你工作
and I sure as hell won't work for you.
我是为了铁路工作  我只会戴这种徽章
I work for the railroad and that's the only kind of badge I'll wear.
对我来说已经够好了  博汉南先生
That's good enough for me, Mr. Bohannon.
当然了  如果事实证明你没办法
Of course, should you prove yourself unable or unwilling
或者不想履行你的职责
to perform your duties at any time,
我会毫不犹豫地上报
I will not hesitate to telegraph the fort.
没必要
Not necessary.
我向你保证
You have my word.
有人吗  我们被锁起来了
Hey! Hey! We're locked in.
我的上帝啊
Sweet baby Jesus.
-着火了  -火
- It's a fire! - Fire!
着火了
It's a fire!
看看锁能不能打开
Check the lock!
快灭火
Get that fire!
扑灭它
Get it!
快开门
Hey, open the door!
开门  神啊
Open them. Jesus.
在枪走火前赶紧挪开
Somebody grab them guns before they go off!
是他  是西德尼·斯诺
It was him. It was Sidney Snow.
米奇
Mickey!
赶紧排队递水  免得整个镇子都烧起来
Organize a bucket brigade before the whole damn town goes up.
好的  大伙
Aye. Right, lads!
所有爱尔兰人  黑鬼牛仔德国佬
Every irish, negro, cowboy and kraut!
都给我拿上水桶
You grab yourselves a bucket!
拯救小镇
Let's save this town!
博汉南先生  我在这儿
Mr. Bohannon, I'm over here!
看在我为您效劳的份上
If you value me service at all,
请您给我利敦瓦纳的妻子带个信
get a message to me sweetheart in Lisdoonvarna.
让她嫁给那个混蛋多尔蒂吧
Tell her go on and marry that bollocks Doherty.
总好过白等我一辈子
Far be it from me to make her an old maid.
闭嘴  培迪
Shut up, Paddy.
这信还是你明天自己写吧
You can write her yourself tomorrow.
我不识字啊  先生
I can't read, sir.
那我就没办法了
Can't help you there.
小心
Watch it!
-弄出来  -水
- Get it out! - Water!
别停
Keep 'em coming.
快把水递过来
Pass the bucket. Come on.
快点  大伙
Quickly lads!
加油  把火扑灭
Come on, get this fire out!
不要停
Keep 'em coming!
快点快点  动作迅速
Come on, faster, faster. Come on, move it out.
好的  孩子们  拿上水桶
All right, boys, pick it up!
总是很高兴能和志同道合的先驱合作
It's always good doin' business with a fellow pioneer,
杨先生
Mr. Young.
请代我感谢您的夫人们在密西西比河两岸
Please, thank all of your wives for the heartiest hospitality
对我的热情招待
I have felt on either side of the Mississippi.
您也会成为圣徒的  亨廷顿先生
We'll make a saint of you yet, Mr. Huntington.
祝您回萨克拉门托的旅途一路顺风
I will pray for your safe return to Sacramento.
我也希望您身体安康  生意兴隆
And I will hope for your continued health and prosperity.
这位  嗯
Oh, uh... Mister, uh...
刚德森先生吧
Gundersen, was it?
我没记错的话这应该是个挪威名字吧
That name is Norwegian if I'm not mistaken.
您没有记错
You are not mistaken.
你为什么想知道我给华工吃什么
Why did you want to know what kind of feed I give my Chinamen?
客人问你话呢  刚德森兄弟
Our guest asked you a question, brother Gundersen.
战争中我知道了
I learned during the war
粮食是军队的灵魂
that an army runs on its stomach,
而工人相当于一支小军队
And what is a labor force if not a small army?
我懂了
I see.
谢谢
Thank you.
我在联太铁路公司待了多年
I spent years on the Union Pacific Railroad
在托马斯·杜兰特手下工作
under Thomas Durant.
那个老混账
Oh, that old son of a gun?
他也给你讲过
He ever give you that damn speech of his
-狮子和斑马的故事吧  -讲了很多次
- about the lion and the zebra? - Oh, many times, yes.
差点把我变成瑞普·凡·温克尔
Oh! 'bout turned me into Rip Van Winkle.
《瑞普·凡·温克尔》是美国作家华盛顿·欧文的著名短篇小说
因为你觉得无聊吗
Because you found it boring?
告诉我  你跟卡伦·博汉南
Tell me, did you ever have the opportunity
一起工作过吗
to work with Cullen Bohannon?
我一辈子记着那个男人
That man impresses the hell out of me.
通过认真研究卡伦·博汉南
Everything I know, I learned
我从他身上学到了很多东西
I learned by careful study of Cullen Bohannon.
是吗
How about that?
我猜我很快就会在坡下见到他了
And I suppose I'll see him on the downslope soon enough.
也许你可以让我这个前联太员工
Perhaps you could use a former Union Pacific man
帮助你的摩门新劳工
to accompany your fresh Mormon workers.
当然了
That is,
如果布里格姆兄弟同意的话
if brother Brigham can spare me.
我们会讨论的
We will discuss it.
退下吧  刚德森
Leave us, Gundersen.
日安
Good day.
你  记得我吗
You. Remember me?
你这垃圾
You no good trash.
救救我
Help... Me...
看着我
Look at me.
Look at me!
我叫伊娃
My name is Eva.
我是母亲  女儿  印第安人
I'm a mother, daughter, Injun,
人妻  也是妓女
wife, and whore.
可我有生以来
But all my time on this earth,
还从没见过比你更垃圾的人
I ain't ever met a bigger piece of shit than you.
他没救了
He couldn't be saved.
看到以斯拉了吗
Have you seen Ezra?
抱歉  没看到
I-I'm sorry, I haven't.
以斯拉还没回来
Ezra hasn't come back.
我待会再跟你们谈
I'll be over after a while.
他从没有整夜不归过
He's never stayed out all night.
好吧  听着
All right. Hey, listen.
房子烧着之前他就逃了
H--h--he run off before all this started.
-他没事的  -可他上哪了
- He's all right. - But--but where is he?
可能只是躲起来了
Probably just tryin' to stay out of the way.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
-以斯拉  -以斯拉
- Ezra! - Ezra!
-快出来  -以斯拉
- Come on out, now! - Ezra!
他不见了吗  露丝
Have you not seen him, Ruth?
男孩就爱乱跑
Oh, you know how boys are.
他应该是躲在什么地方了  以斯拉
He's just hidin' somewheres. Ezra!
以斯拉
Ezra!
-我不会生气的  -以斯拉
- I won't be cross! - Ezra!
求你了  出来吧
Please! Come out!
怎么了
What is it?
后面的屋子
The back room.
不可能  教堂当时没人了
No, church was clear.
在地板下
Under the floor.
露丝
Ruth...
不
No.
别
Please.
-不  -别看
- No! - No, no.
不  放开我
No! Let me--let me go!
西德尼·斯诺  他在哪儿
Sidney Snow. Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
他是你的法警
He's your marshal.
自从他搭上运犯人的火车
I haven't had eyes on him
离开后我就再没见过他
since he left on that prison train!
他听命于你
He takes his orders from you.
那个人谁的命令都不听
Hey, that man's incapable of takin' orders from anyone.
一个小孩丧命了
A child is dead!
我在上帝面前向你发誓
I swear to you before God.
发生在教堂的可耻罪行和我一点儿关系没有
I had nothin' to do with the heinous crimes at the church.
你本应该吊死那个狗娘养的却雇佣了他
You hired that son of bitch when you should have hung him.
你说的对
You're right.
昨晚的悲剧应该怪我
The blame for last night's tragedy is mine.
我就不应该给西德尼·斯诺授权
I never should have empowered Sidney Snow.
我杀过远比你好的人
I've killed far better men than you
他们没这么罪孽深重
for doin' a lot less than that.
我毫不怀疑
I have no shred of doubt.
我愿意提供我权利之内的任何资源
I'd like to offer every resource at my disposal
来帮你找到他并绳之以法
to help you find him and see him hang.
就我看来  你已经没什么资源了
You're all out of resources, far as I can tell.
坎贝尔不知情
Campbell didn't know.
我们搜过赌场  妓院  洗衣店
We searched the casino, the whorehouse, the laundry.
夏安镇的每个老鼠洞都搜过了
Every bleedin' rat hole in Cheyenne.
-再搜一遍  -我已经搜过了
- Search again. - I've searched it already!
他一定是躲在哪里了
He's got to be somewheres.
我亲自监督了搜索过程
I oversaw the search myself.
博汉南
Bohannon.
-你看见他了吗  -没有
- You seen him? - Mm-mm.
这镇上是有很多三教九流
There are a lot of rotten, mangy dogs in this town,
但没人会窝藏一个杀害孩子的凶手
but none who'd shelter a child-killer.
他只用跳上一匹马就能跑路
All he had to was hop on a horse.
他现在恐怕已经快到墨西哥了
He's halfway to Mexico by now,
或者这世上的其它狗屁镇子
or some other arsehole town in this world!
他不在墨西哥
He ain't in Mexico.
卡伦
Cullen!
他已经跑了
He's gone.
结束了
It's over.
我曾有机会杀了他  米奇
I had him, Mickey.
在杂货店的时候
In the general store.
当时我用枪指着他的头
Had my gun to his head.
你为什么没有杀了他
Well, why didn't you shoot him?
露丝...
Ruth...
我们到处都搜遍了
we searched everywheres...
但是我反应太慢了
And I was too slow.
太蠢了
Stupid.
我让西德尼逃脱了
I let Sidney get away.
你第一次把他带来教堂时
When you first brought him to the church,
我就想把他送去孤儿院的
I wanted to send him to the orphanage.
我并没有心思成为谁的母亲
I had no business being anyone's mother.
你当时只是吓坏了
You was just scared.
我一直都不知道他的全名
I never learned his full name.
也不知道他是从哪儿来的
Never knew where he came from.
不知道他有没有兄弟姐妹
Whether he had brothers or sisters
不知道他家里都有什么人
Or what became of his family.
不知道他小时候幸不幸福
I don't know if he was a colicky baby or a happy one
不知道他的眼睛像不像他的父亲
or if his eyes were like his father's.
他永远也上不了学了
He'll never go to school.
永远也找不到心上人
Never have a sweetheart.
永远无法结婚
Never get married.
他讨厌做家务
He hated doing chores.
他把活的癞蛤蟆带进教堂
He brought live toads into the church.
他又野又固执
He was wild and headstrong...
我一直都没办法让他洗个澡
and I could never get him to take a bath.
但他是个好孩子
But he was a good boy.
我见他最后一面时
And the last time I saw him,
我还冲他发脾气了
I spoke to him in anger.
不  不
No. No.
你当时只是试图保护他
You was just tryin' to protect him.
保护的还真好啊
The good it did.
你也不知道会发生这种事
You didn't know.
我应该察觉到的
I should've known!
我应该照顾好他的
I was supposed to take care of him.
我永远也不配当个母亲了
I never deserved to be a mother.
布里格姆兄弟
Ah, brother Brigham.
日安
Good day.
你给克利斯·亨廷顿留了个好印象
You made a favorable impression on Collis Huntington.
我们商量过了
We discussed
你将陪着圣徒们去中太平洋工作
your accompanying the saints to work on the Central Pacific.
他希望你独自前往
He'd like you along.
真是个有远见的人  就像您一样
Truly a man of vision, like yourself.
圣灵促使我奔向他  靠近他
The holy spirit compelled me to--to reach out to him.
上帝在俗世上的先知是我
I am God's prophet on earth.
不是你
Not you.
原谅我  布里格姆兄弟
Forgive me, brother Brigham.
我被自大冲昏了头
I was bested by my pride.
圣父对你自有安排
Heavenly father has plans for you here.
将来  你必须牢记自己的位置
In the future, it would behoove you to remember your place.
当然
Of course.
谢谢您
Oh, thank you,
*主的狮子啊*
*Oh lion of the lord*
快穿好衣服  去做祷告
Finish dressing and pray.
再过半小时就要开教区会议了
There's a ward meeting in half an hour.
[挪威语]
伊娃  我看到你干了什么
Eva, I saw what you did.
我干了什么
What'd I do?
你杀了那个人
You killed that man.
就在那场大火之后
After the fire.
我知道他残酷可怕
I know he was monstrous.
你只知道华丽的辞藻
You don't know nothin' but words.
伊娃
Eva.
我知道
I know.
他也干了你
He done you, too.
你杀了他
You murdered him.
也算不上谋杀
Weren't exactly murder.
你怎么能那么做
How could you do it?
我发现你并没有试图阻止我
I notice you didn't try to stop me.
不是
No.
我是说我
I mean I--
我...我就做不到
I...couldn't have done it.
没事  埃里森小姐
It's all right, Miss Ellison.
这不是你的错
You ain't done nothin' wrong.
如果你在这里待了够久  经历了够多事
Enough things happen to you long enough out here,
你也什么都能做出来
you can do anything.
等着瞧吧
You'll see.
别读了
Don't.
你总是伴他左右  露丝
You was always there for him, Ruth.
这对他来说很重要
That means a lot.
你自己的儿子也死于暴行
You lost your own son to violence.
是的  乔舒亚
Yeah, Joshua.
他跟以斯拉差不多大
He's about Ezra's age.
你怎么能忍呢
How do you endure it?
没有什么能让你心安
Ain't nothin' brings peace.
等你找到那个杀死我孩子的恶魔
When you find the devil who did this to my child,
我希望你把他送回地狱
I hope you return him to hell with my wish
让他深陷苦海
that his suffering be deep,
永劫不复
and eternal.
早上好
Good morning.
有老鼠吗
Rats?
更像是幽灵吧
It's ghosts, more like.
是啊
Yes, well...
汉娜离开我的时候  我...
When Hannah left me, I...
我其实更喜欢独自待在牢房里
I actually preferred the solitude of my prison cell
而不是待在空荡荡的家里
to the empty rooms of the family house.
别因为你的新工作
Don't let your new duties
耽误你征服谢尔曼峰
keep you from conquering Sherman peak.
我在写一篇文章
I'm writing an article
关于夏安镇的司法行政
about the administration of justice in Cheyenne.
恐怕你不会喜欢的
I don't think you're going to like it.
该死
Ah, damn it!
它可不是个娇小姐啊  博汉南先生
Not a delicate lady, Mr. Bohannon.
它是个
What we have here
虎背熊腰的婊子
is a strong-backed, thick-thighed whore.
我建议你用管道扳手
I'd recommend a plumbing wrench.
那就管道扳手吧  德莱尼先生
Plumbing wrench it is, Mr. Delaney.
德莱尼先生
Mr. Delaney?
谢谢
Thank you.
假设我们
Supposin' now we, um...
把你的这个设备修好了
get this contraption of your'n on up and runnin'.
恐怕对工人们不是好事
Won't find it friend to the workin' man.
只要别让我被乱石砸死
Anything that keeps me droppin' dead chuckin' rock
就是好事
is a friend of mine.
如果这台蒸汽挖土机真像你说的
This steam shovel of your'n chew up Sherman Peak
能荡平谢尔曼峰
like you say,
那老帕萨姆还有什么用
What use is old Psalms?
你也没用了
Or you, while we at it?
这是明天的问题
Tomorrow's problem.
把扳手给我
Hand me that wrench right there.
卡伦·博汉南
Cullen Bohannon!
你这个南方佬谋杀犯快滚出来
Get your blue coat killin' ass out here, now!
我在这里  西德
I'm right here, Sid!
你最好跟我聊聊
You best come and talk to me 'fore
不然我会把这狗屎城镇射个稀巴烂
I shoot the piss out of this pig shit town!
好的
All right.
我们聊聊
Let's talk.
瞧瞧你
Well, look at you.
你嫉妒我有警徽
You're jealous of my badge.
于是自己也去搞了一枚
you had to go out and get one for yourself.
你不该回来的
You should have kept ridin'.
我也这样觉得
Yeah, I thought so too.
我都快到丹佛了
You know, I was half way to Denver
才返身回来烧了那个北方妞的教堂
after I set that cute lil' yankee twist's church on fire.
你知道我为什么回来吗
You know what it was made me come back?
因为你
It was you.
博汉南
Bohannon.
我们有些事没了结
You and me got unfinished business.
恐怕是的
Suppose that's right.
我们现在解决了怎么样
What do you say we settle things right now?
我不想再杀人了
I'm all done with killin'.
或许你会被杀
Well, maybe you gonna get killed.
我会逮捕你的
I'm gonna arrest you.
你为什么不过来试试
Well, why don't you come on over here and try.
放下枪
Drop that gun.
好  过来拿啊
Yeah, come on and take it.
真他妈绝了
Well, dip me in dog shit.
教堂妞
The church lady?